Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 138 Records WAG.153
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 138 Records
1936-1992
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Brotherhood of Teamsters. Local 138
Ruscigno, Michael
WAG.153
10.75 Linear Feet in 9 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, and 1 oversize flat box
The International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 138 Records (dated 1936-1992) contain contracts, minutes, elections records, and documents related to arbitrations, mediations, and disputes between union members and their employers. Local 138 (Furniture, Flour and Grocery Teamsters and Chauffeurs) was chartered in 1927 and is one of the earliest Teamster locals in New York City. The bulk of the collection consists of shop files reflecting the bargaining efforts of Local 138, which include contracts and agreements between Local 138 and employers. Other materials include 3 bound cash books tracking union expenses (1936-1939), mediations (1964-1980), executive board minutes (1944-1962), National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) disputes and complaints, and election records (1943-1968).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Michael Ruscigno, Recording Secretary of Local 138, circa 1996. The accession number associated with this gift is 1986.014.
Arrangement
Files in this collection are in rough groupings by topic and document type. This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Historical/Biographical Note
The International Brother Hood of Teamsters, Local 138 (Furniture, Flour and Grocery Teamsters and Chauffeurs) was chartered in 1927 and therefore is one of the earliest Teamster locals in New York City. The charter was amended in 1940 to include the City of Brooklyn. The Local has suffered declining membership since the 1980s as a result of the loss of small businesses and downsizing. The Local conducted a prolonged and costly strike after the takeover of White Rose Foods by Arthur M. Goldberg in 1990.
Scope and Content Note
The International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 138 Records (dated 1936-1992) contain contracts, minutes, elections records, and documents related to arbitrations, mediations, and disputes between union members and their employers.
The bulk of the collection consists of shop files reflecting the bargaining efforts of Local 138. These files contain contracts and agreements between Local 138 and employers, as well as a small amount of correspondence and notes related to bargaining efforts. Contracts between the union and employers largely feature grocery stores, furniture companies, warehouses, moving companies, freight companies, and various merchants. Some contracts are dated as early as early as 1938, but the majority date from the mid-1960s to the 1980s.
Other materials include 3 bound cash books tracking union expenses (1936-1939), mediations (1964-1980), executive board minutes (1944-1962), National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) disputes and complaints, and election records (1943-1968).
Labor disputes -- New York (State) -- New York.; Warehouses -- New York (State) -- New York.; Truck drivers -- Labor unions -- United States.; Collective bargaining.; Collective labor agreements -- Trucking industry; Teamsters for a Democratic Union; International Brotherhood of Teamsters. Local 138; Ruscigno, Michael
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters Stamps, undated (Box 1)
- Account Ledger, 1940 (Box 1)
- Assorted Pamphlets and Publications, 1956-1996 (Box 1)
- Shop Files: Employment Records -- L. Ender Inc., Progresso, and Embassy Grocery, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
- Teamsters for a Democratic Union, Local 138, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
- "New Beginnings" Slate, 1986 (Box 1)
- Mediation Notices, 1968-1980 (Box 1)
- Arbitration Awards, 1978-1987 (Box 1)
- National Labor Relations Board -- Goya Foods, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- Shop Files: Bargaining Files -- United Parcel Service, 1938-1977 (Box 2)
- Shop Files: Bargaining Files -- General, 1954-1981 (Box 2)
- Shop Files: Bargaining Files -- Trucking and Grocery Companies, 1953-1980 (Box 3)
- Eastern Conference of Teamsters, 1964-1972 (Box 4)
- Joint Council 16, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1966-1976 (Box 4)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters -- Democrat, Republican, Independent Voter Education (DRIVE), 1962-1964 (Box 4)
- Maritime Port Council, 1964-1967 (Box 4)
- Employer Complaints, 1970-1979 (Box 4)
- Shop Files: Bargaining Files -- Grocery Stores, 1952-1979 (Box 4, Box 5)
- Freight Contract Guide, 1976-1979 (Box 5)
- National Labor Relations Board Organizing, 1987-1990 (Box 5)
- Shop Files: Bargaining Files -- I-W, 1956-1980 (Box 5)
- National Labor Relations Board Cases, 1971-1980 (Box 5)
- Shop Files: Bargaining Files -- C-P, 1952-1985 (Box 6)
- Executive Board Minutes, 1945-1962 (Box 7)
- Elections, 1943-1972 (Box 7, Box 8)
- Shop Files: Bargaining Files -- A-W, 1976-1992 (Box 8, Box 9)
- National Labor Relations Board Complaints, 1987-1989 (Box 9)
- Shop Files: Bargaining Files and Employer Complaints, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Box 10)
- Cash Books, 1936-1939 (Box 11)